The Ganges,the longest river in India
恒河,印度最长的河流
On its epic journey from the world's highest mountains
从世界最高的山脉开始史诗般的旅程
through cultivated farmland,
通过耕地,
sprawling wilderness to the Indian Ocean,
蔓延到印度洋的旷野,
it provides a home to some of India's rarest creatures.
它为一些印度最稀有的生物提供了家园.
And a lifeline to millions of people.
这是成千上万人的生命线.
Considered a goddess to Hindus,
被认为是印度教徒的女神,
the Ganges harbors one of the great contradictions
恒河蕴藏着巨大的矛盾之一
of life in India.
印度的生活
The river people most cherish is the river
人们最珍惜的河是河
they most pollute.
他们最污染.
But the Ganges hides life-sustaining secrets.
但是恒河隐藏着维持生命的秘密.
From its origins in the Himalayas,
从喜马拉雅山脉的起源
the Ganges flows over two and a half thousand kilometers
恒河流过两千五百公里
across Northern India before emptying into the ocean
排入印度洋之前穿越印度北部
on the border of India and Bangladesh.
在印度和孟加拉国的边界上.
This mighty river is home
这条大河就是家
to some of the rarest and strangest animals on the planet,
对于地球上一些最稀有和最奇怪的动物,
including elusive river dolphins
包括难以捉摸的河豚
and bizarre long-nosed reptiles.
和奇怪的长鼻爬行动物.
The Ganges also supports some of the last true wilderness
恒河还支持一些最后的真实荒野
in the world,
在世界上,
where India's largest population of tigers still thrives.
印度最大的老虎种群仍在这里繁衍生息.
Nourished by sediment washed from the Himalayas,
从喜马拉雅山冲走的沉积物滋养着,
the Gangetic Plains are some
恒河平原是一些
of the most fertile land on earth
地球上最肥沃的土地
and home to India's giants.
并且是印度巨人的故乡.
But man has reaped rewards too.
但是人也获得了回报.
Vast areas of natural habitat haven been destroyed
广阔的自然栖息地遭到破坏
to make way for farming and industry.
为农业和工业让路.
Half a billion people live in the Ganges Basin,
恒河盆地有五亿人口
8% of the world's population.
占世界人口的8％.
The river not only provides livelihoods and drinking water.
这条河不仅提供了生计和饮用水.
It carries away the sewage and waste of millions.
它带走了数百万的污水和废物.
For Hindus,the Ganges is far more than a river.
对于印度教徒而言,恒河不仅仅是一条河.
She's a goddess,Ganga.
她是女神,甘加.
The grime of thousands of people taking a holy bath filters
数千人的污垢洗了圣浴过滤器
into the water every day
每天都下水
Offerings to the goddess
给女神的奉献
and human cremations on the banks add
银行的人类火葬增加了
to the strain on the river.
在河上的压力.
But despite this,unique properties in Ganges water
但是尽管如此,恒河水中的独特属性
could explain how rare creatures
可以解释稀有生物
and rich vegetation are able to survive.
丰富的植被能够生存.
Hindu belief in the goddess Ganga's power
印度教信仰女神恒河的力量
to purify could prove to be more than just blind faith.
净化不只是盲目的信仰.
The Ganges starts its life among the highest mountains
恒河开始在最高的山脉中生活
in the world,the Himalayas.
在世界上,喜马拉雅山.
Many of the peaks reach over 6,000 meters
许多山峰超过6,000米
and are constantly covered in snow and ice.
并不断被雪和冰覆盖.
Over 15,000 glaciers make this the world's largest store
超过15,000个冰川使之成为世界上最大的商店
of fresh water outside the polar ice caps.
极地冰盖外的淡水.
The Gangotri Glacier is one of the largest.
甘戈特里冰川是最大的冰川之一.
The glacier stretches for 30 kilometers
冰川绵延30公里
and fills a valley with solid ice.
并用固体冰填满山谷.
Its leading edge is called Gaumukh,the cow's mouth,
它的前缘叫Gaumukh,牛的嘴,
as the water which flows under its vast icy tongue
就像是在其冰冷的舌头下流淌的水一样
is milky white.
是乳白色的.
Hindus consider this to be the source of the Ganges.
印度教徒认为这是恒河的源头.
Only the hardiest pilgrims come and worship here.
只有最艰难的朝圣者来这里敬拜.
It said that if you drink at Gaumukh,
它说,如果您在Gaumukh喝酒,
you'll live for 100 years.
你会活一百年.
But the true headwaters of the Ganges begin
但是恒河的真正源头开始了
above the glacier,
在冰川之上
nearly four and a half thousand meters above sea level.
海拔近四千五百米
Few animals can survive in this harsh environment.
在这种恶劣的环境中,很少有动物能够生存.
A Himalayan blue sheep's dense fur helps insulate it
喜马拉雅蓝绵羊的茂密皮毛有助于绝缘
against the cold,but even here,predators are on the prowl.
抵御寒冷,但即使在这里,掠食者也在四处寻觅.
Snow leopards are perfectly adapted to mountain life.
雪豹非常适合山区生活.
Wooly fur keeps out the cold wind.
毛茸茸的皮毛挡住了冷风.
Its long,thick tail can be wrapped around its body,
它的长而粗的尾巴可以包裹在身体上,
like a scarf.
像围巾
Even the soles of its feet are covered with fur,
甚至它的脚底都被皮毛覆盖,
for extra warmth.
为您带来额外的温暖.
Minerals in rocks supplement a blue sheep's meager diet,
岩石中的矿物质补充了蓝羊的微薄饮食,
but they need to be eaten with care.
但需要小心食用.
Rock falls are common.
岩崩很常见.
Constant freeze and thaw makes mountain slopes unstable
不断的冻结和融化使山坡不稳定
A blue sheep which has lost its footing is an easy meal.
失去立足点的蓝羊是一顿轻松的饭.
Snow melt from the Himalayas continually feeds the Ganges.
来自喜马拉雅山脉的积雪不断地滋养恒河.
Hindu mythology tells that Ganga,the river goddess,
印度神话告诉我们,河女神甘加（Ganga）
originally flowed through the heavens.
最初流过天堂.
She was brought to earth by a devout king,Bhagiratha,
她由虔诚的国王巴吉拉塔（Bhagiratha）带到世上,
whose ancestors had been turned to ashes by an angry sage.
他们的祖先被愤怒的圣人化为灰烬.
The goddess Ganga agreed to come and release
恒河女神同意来释放
these trapped souls.
这些被困的灵魂.
But warned that her torrential power
但是警告说她的洪流力量
would wash the world away.
会洗净世界.
Bhagiratha petitioned Lord Shiva for help.
Bhagiratha向湿婆大人求助.
Shiva put his matted hair in the path
湿婆把他乱蓬蓬的头发放在路上
of the heavenly river.
天河的.
His dreadlocks absorbed the torrent's destructive force
他的辫子吸收了洪流的破坏力
and split the deluge into a thousand smaller streams.
并将洪水分成几千条较小的溪流.
The fast flowing mountain brooks are full of insect larvae
快速流动的山间小溪里充满了昆虫幼虫
and an ideal hunting ground for a brown dipper.
和一个理想的狩猎场,一个棕色的北斗星.
Weighing less than 100 grams,
重量不到100克,
these small birds seem likely
这些小鸟似乎很可能
to be washed away by the current,
被潮流冲走,
but they're well adapted to forage for food
但它们很适合觅食
in the rocky stream bed.
在多岩石的河床上.
The short wings are strong enough to swim under water
短的翅膀足够坚固,可以在水下游泳
and their blood stores more oxygen than terrestrial birds,
而且他们的血液比陆生鸟类存储更多的氧气,
allowing them to hold their breath for half a minute,
让他们屏住呼吸半分钟,
ample time to grab a beak full.
有足够的时间抓住喙.
The young Ganges River that flows from the Gangotri Glacier
从甘戈特里冰川流出的年轻恒河
is called Bhagirathi,in honor of the king
被称为Bhagirathi,以纪念国王
that brought the river goddess to earth.
把河女神带到了人间.
50 kilometers downstream,
下游50公里,
the turbulent Bhagirathi collides
湍急的巴吉拉提相撞
with one of its sister streams,
与它的一个姐妹流一起,
the sedate and muddy Alaknanda.
宁静而浑浊的阿拉克南达.
The two run alongside each other for 200 meters
两人并排跑了200米
before their waters mix.
在他们的水混合之前.
This river is now called Ganges.
这条河现在称为恒河.
Raging water calms as the river reaches the flat lands
随着河流到达平坦的土地,汹涌的河水平静下来
of the Gangetic Plains.
恒河平原.
Sediments carried from high among the glaciers are released.
冰川中高处的沉积物被释放.
The Ganges deposits 1.6 billion tons of sediment every year,
恒河每年沉积16亿吨沉积物,
four times as much as the Amazon.
是亚马逊的四倍
This creates some of the most fertile land in the world.
这创造了世界上最肥沃的土地.
The Ganges River Basin covers a million square kilometers
恒河流域面积达一百万平方公里
of Northeastern India.
印度东北部.
Much of this huge flood plain has been farmed,
这个巨大的洪泛平原大部分已被耕种,
but a few pockets of wild grassland and forest survive
但是有几片野草和森林幸存下来
among the river's furthest tributaries
在河最远的支流之中
in a region known as the Terai.
在被称为Terai的地区
The Terai is home to one of the largest animals
Terai是最大的动物之一的家
in the world,the Indian rhino.
在世界上,印度犀牛.
Males can weigh up to 3000 kilos,
雄性重达3000公斤,
twice the weight of the average family car.
是普通家庭汽车重量的两倍.
Indian rhinos once roamed right across the Gangetic Plains.
印度犀牛曾经在恒河平原上漫游.
But now are found in just a few protected areas.
但是现在仅在几个保护区中被发现.
Their single horn can grow to over half a meter in length.
它们的单角长度可以超过半米.
Their prehensile lip makes their mouths
他们唇边张开的嘴唇
almost as nimble as a hand.
几乎像一只手一样敏捷.
They can grasp tufts of grass and pick up fruit and leaves.
他们可以抓住一簇草,捡起水果和树叶.
Rhinos eyesight is poor,but their sense of smell is sharp.
犀牛的视力较差,但嗅觉敏锐.
Scent glands on their feet leave a pungent trail
脚上的气味腺留下刺鼻的痕迹
wherever they walk back.
无论他们走到哪里.
At midday,pre-monsoon heat nudges temperatures
在中午,季风前的热量推动温度升高
into the 40s.
进入40年代.
Rhinos seek refuge in the river.
犀牛在河里寻求庇护.
As they are the most aquatic of all rhinos,
由于它们是所有犀牛中最水生的,
a calf's first lesson is how to swim.
小牛的第一课是游泳.
Indian rhinos are more tolerant of company
印度犀牛更宽容公司
than their African cousins and often bathe together.
比他们的非洲表兄弟还经常洗澡.
But tempers fray when females are on heat
但是,当女性受热时,脾气会发散
Battles over breeding rights can be bloody
关于育种权的斗争可能是血腥的
Thick,warty folds around a male's neck
粗壮的疣状褶皱环绕在男性的脖子上
offer some protection.
提供一些保护.
But fights like this often lead to death.
但是像这样的战斗往往会导致死亡.
The reward for the victorious male is the right to mate.
胜利男性的报酬是交配的权利.
In 16 months,the female will give birth to one calf.
在16个月内,雌性将生一头小牛.
It will be two to three years
这将是两到三年
before she's ready to mate again.
在她准备再次交配之前.
The floodplains of the Ganges in Northern India contain
印度北部恒河的洪泛区包含
some of the world's most fertile soil.
一些世界上最肥沃的土壤.
Nearly 500 million people live in the Ganges River Basin.
恒河流域有近5亿人居住.
It's one of the most densely populated places on earth.
这是地球上人口最稠密的地方之一.
Wildlife is under increasing pressure
野生动物的压力越来越大
from the huge number of people
来自大量的人
sharing the river's resources.
共享河流的资源.
Ganges water is naturally muddy.
恒河水自然是浑浊的.
Runoff from farming and industry makes it murkier still,
农业和工业的径流使它更加阴暗,
but there are animals living here.
但是这里有动物.
One creature is seen so rarely,it seems almost mythical.
很少见到一种生物,这几乎是神话.
The Gangetic river dolphin spends most
恒河海豚花费最多
of its time foraging for food.
觅食的时间.
Visibility in the water is so poor
在水中的能见度很差
that the dolphins eyes have lost their lenses.
海豚的眼睛失去了晶状体.
They're almost completely blind and use echolocation
他们几乎完全失明,使用回声定位
to navigate and detect prey.
导航并检测猎物.
Like its marine cousins,
像它的海洋堂兄弟一样,
the river dolphin is a mammal
河豚是哺乳动物
and has to surface every few minutes to breathe.
并且每隔几分钟就要浮出水面来呼吸.
Local people call it susu after the sound it makes
声音发出后,当地人称它为susu
when it takes in air through the blow hole
当它通过吹孔吸入空气时
on the top of its head.
在它的头顶上.
The elusive susu isn't the only strange creature
难以捉摸的苏苏不是唯一的奇怪生物
to call the Ganges home.
叫恒河回家.
These armor plates belong
这些装甲板属于
to one of the largest crocodilians in the world,
到世界上最大的鳄鱼之一,
the gharial.
加里尔.
Male gharials can grow to be six meters long.
雄性咽喉可以长到六米.
This prehistoric-looking predator poses no threat to man
这个看起来像史前的捕食者对人类没有威胁
Its long slender jaws are too delicate
它的细长的下巴太细腻了
to tackle large mammals.
解决大型哺乳动物.
They're adapted to hunt fish.
他们适合打鱼.
A slim-line snout whips through the water with little drag.
一条细长的鼻子几乎没有阻力地穿过水鞭打.
Slippery fish is skewered on rows of razor sharp teeth.
滑溜的鱼串在剃须刀锋利的牙齿上.
Tiny pits in their scales detect vibrations
秤上的微小凹坑可检测到振动
in the water and help pinpoint prey.
在水中,帮助查明猎物.
Male gharials develop a bump at the end of their noses
男性鼻咽部在鼻子的末端形成隆起
called a gharra,after the Hindi word for pot.
在印地语单词pot之后,叫做gharra.
The bigger the gharra,
贫民窟越大,
the more attractive a male is to a mate,
男性对伴侣越有魅力,
but a female may hear her suitor before she sees him.
但女性在见到求婚者之前可能会先听见他的求婚者.
Air squeezed through the male's nostrils is amplified
通过雄性鼻孔挤压的空气被放大
by his bulbous snout.
通过他的球茎吻.
It becomes a loud buzzing sound
变成嗡嗡声
that can be heard up to a kilometer away.
一公里外都能听到.
A female raises her head,a sign she's ready to male.
一位女性举起她的头,这是她准备向男性展示的迹象.
The courting couple slip under the cover of water
求爱的夫妻在水的掩护下滑倒
and stay submerged up to half an hour.
并保持淹没时间长达半小时.
Females lay their eggs on sandy riverbanks.
女性在沙质河岸上产卵.
Gharials are much better adapted to life in water.
加里尔人更好地适应了水中的生活.
On land,the female's short legs
在陆地上,女性的短腿
can't lift her body clear of the ground.
无法将她的身体抬离地面.
Under the cover of darkness,
在黑暗的掩护下,
she buries up to 100 eggs.
她埋了多达100个鸡蛋.
Sand acts as an incubator.
沙子充当孵化器.
It absorbs the sun's warmth
吸收阳光的温暖
and keeps the eggs between 30 and 34 degrees Celsius.
并将鸡蛋保持在30到34摄氏度之间.
The mother guards her nest for two months
母亲把她的窝守了两个月
while her eggs develop.
当她的卵发育时.
The eggs are some of the largest in the crocodile world
鸡蛋是鳄鱼世界中最大的鸡蛋
and make a tasty meal for a jackal or a monitor lizard.
并为a狼或监控蜥蜴做一顿美味的饭.
Gharials are an ancient species,over 60 million years old.
加里尔人是一种古老的物种,已有六千万年的历史.
Just 60 years ago,there were thought
就在60年前,
to be as many as 10,000 living wild.
多达10,000只野生动物.
Today,there are fewer than 200.
今天,少于200个.
They've been hunted for their meat and skins
他们为了肉和皮而被猎杀
and for the males gharra,
对于雄性加拉,
which some people believe is an aphrodisiac.
有些人认为这是一种壮阳药.
As the Ganges banks succumb to agriculture and industry,
随着恒河银行屈服于农业和工业,
their habitat is being destroyed too.
他们的栖息地也被破坏了.
Human pressure has pushed gharials
人为的压力已经推高了鼻息肉
to the brink of extinction,
濒临灭绝,
but for Hindus,the worship,protection,
但是对于印度教徒来说,崇拜,保护,
and feeding of animals is key to their faith.
喂养动物是他们信仰的关键.
Usi Sahami rows across the Ganges every morning.
乌西萨哈米每天早上划船穿过恒河.
Feeding gulls has been her daily ritual for 20 years.
喂海鸥是她20多年来的日常习惯.
She considers it her duty as a Hindu
她认为这是她作为印度教徒的责任
and believes it will help her achieve a better existence
并相信这将帮助她获得更好的生活
in the next life.
在来世.
Reincarnation is a core belief of Hinduism.
转世是印度教的核心信念.
Nowhere is this more evident
这是最明显的地方
than in Usi's hometown,Varanasi.
比在乌西的家乡瓦拉纳西要大.
Varanasi is at the heart of the Ganges
瓦拉纳西是恒河的核心
and is considered to be the holiest place in India.
并被认为是印度最圣洁的地方.
It's one of the oldest cities in the world.
它是世界上最古老的城市之一.
People have been coming here to bathe in the Ganges
人们一直来这里在恒河中沐浴
for over 3000 years.
已有3000多年的历史了.
The water is believed to wash away sins and purify the soul.
人们相信水可以洗净罪恶并净化灵魂.
Every Hindu dreams of visiting the Ganges,
每个印度教徒都梦想着参观恒河,
But the many who comes to Varanasi,it's the last journey
但是很多来瓦拉纳西的人,这是最后的旅程
they'll ever make.
他们会做的.
Varanasi is a city of death.
瓦拉纳西是死亡之城.
Hindus believe every soul is locked
印度教徒相信每个灵魂都被锁住
in a perpetual cycle of birth and reincarnation,
在出生和轮回的永恒循环中,
known as samsara.
被称为轮回.
Death is just one link in the chain.
死亡只是链条中的一环.
The scent of sandalwood,incense,and ghee fills the air.
檀香,熏香和酥油的气味弥漫在空气中.
Funeral pyres burn round the clock.
丧葬的柴火全天候燃烧.
Varanasi is considered to be a gateway
瓦拉纳西被认为是门户
between heaven and earth.
在天地之间.
To die and be cremated here is believed
人们相信这里要死而被火化
to ease the soul on its journey to the next life.
减轻灵魂通往下世的旅程.
The ultimate goal is to escape the suffering
最终目标是逃避苦难
of repeated lives and attain moksha,release.
重复生活并获得释放.
For the untouchable Dom caste,Varanasi's undertakers,
对于瓦拉纳西不可动摇的唐种姓,
death is a way of life.
死亡是一种生活方式.
The Doms keep Varanasi's fires burning.
大教堂使瓦拉纳西的大火不断燃烧.
They sell the wood and prepare bodies for cremation.
他们出售木材,准备尸体进行火化.
The chief undertaker,the Dom Raja,
首席承办者Dom Raja
guards an eternal flame from which all pyres must be lit.
守护永恒的火焰,必须点燃所有柴堆.
An average of 250 cremations take place
平均火化250次
on the burning ghats every day.
每天都在燃烧的西高止山脉上.
The ashes of thousands are scattered
成千上万的骨灰散落
in the Ganges River each year.
每年在恒河.
When the funeral is over,religious devotion dissolves
葬礼结束后,宗教奉献化为乌有.
into raw reality once more.
再次进入原始现实.
The Doms sift through their client's remains,
Doms筛选客户的遗体,
looking for spoils.
寻找战利品.
They're rumor to collect up to seven grams
他们有谣言说要收集七克
of gold teeth and earrings every day.
每天都有金色的牙齿和耳环.
In Varanasi,the spiritual and the mundane go hand-in-hand.
在瓦拉纳西,精神与世俗并驾齐驱.
Pilgrims wash while they worship
朝圣者在崇拜时会洗
and pollute as they purify.
当他们净化时会污染.
The Ganges is one of the most polluted rivers in the world.
恒河是世界上污染最严重的河流之一.
Yet the life-sustaining power of Ganges water
然而恒河的生命维持能力
has been recognized for hundreds of years.
已经被认可了数百年.
In the 16th century,the Mughal Emperor Akbar called it
在16世纪,莫卧儿皇帝阿克巴（Ambar）称其为
the water of immortality.
不朽之水.
He would serve nothing else to his guests
他不会为客人服务
because it tasted so sweet.
因为它味道真甜.
200 years later,
200年后
the British East India Company regularly stocked ships
英国东印度公司定期备货船只
with barrels of Ganges water.
每桶恒河水.
They claimed no other water stayed as fresh
他们声称没有其他水能保持如此新鲜
for the three-month journey back to England
三个月的旅程回到英格兰
Today,despite huge numbers gathering
今天,尽管人数众多
to bathe,often where raw sewage drains into the river,
洗澡,通常是原始污水流进河里的地方
there have been no recorded outbreaks
没有记录的爆发
of major diseases like cholera or typhoid.
霍乱或伤寒等重大疾病.
Hindus insist Ganges water has the power to purify.
印度教徒坚持认为恒河水具有净化能力.
Maybe there is more to this claim than meets the eye.
也许这种说法不仅仅令人眼前一亮.
The lower reaches of India's Ganges River Basin
印度恒河流域的下游
are so fertile,the locals call the area
如此肥沃,当地人称该地区
the Rice Bowl of India.
印度的饭碗.
Farmers reap four rice harvests a year here,
农民每年在这里收获四次稻米,
double that of many parts of the country.
是该国许多地区的两倍.
But these fertile fields bring dangers of their own.
但是这些肥沃的土地带来了自己的危险.
A deadly monocled cobra feasts on a toad.
致命的眼镜蛇在蟾蜍上大吃一顿.
Common prey in a paddy field.
在稻田中的常见猎物.
The snake's hunting trip brings it
蛇的狩猎之旅带来了它
perilously close to farmers harvesting rice.
危险地接近收割水稻的农民.
A million people in India are bitten by snakes every year.
每年印度有100万人被蛇咬伤.
Monocled cobras are one of the most venomous snakes in Asia.
单眼镜蛇是亚洲最有毒的蛇之一.
Fangs inject poison
ang牙注射毒药
that paralyzes its victim's nervous system
瘫痪受害者的神经系统
and breaks down its cells.
并分解其细胞.
One bite can kill a man in less than an hour.
咬一口就能在不到一个小时的时间内杀死一个人.
Many people here have an understandable fear of snakes,
这里很多人对蛇的恐惧是可以理解的,
but in the village of Chhoto Poshla in West Bengal,
但是在西孟加拉邦的Chhoto Poshla村,
the attitude towards these deadly serpents
对这些致命蛇的态度
is rather more surprising.
更加令人惊讶.
Snakes are drawn to the village in search of rodents,
蛇被吸引到村庄寻找啮齿动物,
often found around human settlements.
通常在人类住区周围发现.
A rat in the larder is one thing.
储藏室里的老鼠是一回事.
A cobra in the bedroom,quite another.
卧室里的眼镜蛇,又是另一只.
But instead of causing panic,
但是,除了引起恐慌之外,
the venomous visitor raises not so much as an eyebrow.
有毒的访客举得不如眉毛.
Villagers here don't just tolerate snakes.
这里的村民不仅仅容忍蛇.
They worship them.
他们崇拜他们.
The village priest is summoned
村牧师被传唤
to relocate the revered intruder.
迁移受人尊敬的入侵者.
He's the only one permitted to handle them.
他是唯一允许他们处理的人.
Chhoto Poshla's 6,000 residents share the village
Chhoto Poshla的6,000名居民与村民共享
with 3000 monocled cobras.
与3000只眼镜蛇.
Village elders tell the tale
村里的长者讲这个故事
that snakes arrived six centuries ago to seek refuge
六个世纪前蛇到达避难所
from a huge flood.
从一场巨大的洪水中
Flood water brought with it remarkable rice production.
洪水带来了显著的水稻产量.
Snakes have been associated with prosperity ever since.
从那时起,蛇就与繁荣联系在一起.
When he's not removing snakes from people's homes,
当他不把蛇从人们的家中移走时,
Shyamal Chakrabarti leads the worship in the village temple.
Shyamal Chakrabarti带领村里的寺庙进行朝拜.
Villagers make offerings of fruit and sweets
村民们奉献水果和糖果
to the snake goddess Manasa,
对蛇女神玛娜莎,
who they believe keeps their fields flourishing
他们相信谁可以保持自己的领域蓬勃发展
and their people safe from snakebite.
他们的人民免受蛇咬.
When a dead snake is found,
当发现一条死蛇时,
Shyamal carries its body to the Ganges
Shyamal将尸体运送到恒河
so it can continue its journey of reincarnation.
这样它才能继续轮回的旅程.
As well as a sacred burial site for humans and animals,
以及人类和动物的圣地,
the Ganges also provides a hunting ground
恒河还提供了狩猎场
for one of the world's most skillful aquatic predators.
世界上最熟练的水族捕食者之一.
Smooth-coated otters are in their element underwater.
光滑涂层的水獭在水下是其元素.
Ears and nostrils close to keep water out
耳朵和鼻孔靠近以防积水
as they propel themselves with powerful webbed hind feet
当他们用有力的蹼状后脚推动自己时
and a strong flattened tail.
和强壮扁平的尾巴.
Thick velvety coats provide a streamlined surface,
厚实的天鹅绒大衣可提供流线型表面,
crucial to the high-speed pursuit of fish.
对鱼类的高速追捕至关重要.
An otter can change direction in a flash.
水獭可以瞬间改变方向.
Sensitive whiskers detect the slightest movement of prey.
灵敏的胡须可以检测到猎物的丝毫动静.
Unlike other otters,
与其他水獭不同
smooth-coated otters are social animals.
光滑的水獭是社交动物.
Family groups of as many as 17 share a territory
多达17个家庭团体共享一个领地
led by a dominant female.
由占主导地位的女性领导.
Wriggling against each other helps dry their coats
互相扭动有助于使外套变干
and reinforces bonds.
并加强纽带.
Otters work as a team when they hunt,
水獭狩猎时会团队合作,
corralling shoals of fish and sharing the spoils,
围住鱼群和共享战利品,
But they aren't the only fishermen on the river.
但是他们并不是河上唯一的渔民.
Sachin Bishwash has made his living on the Ganges
萨钦·巴什瓦什（Sachin Bishwash）靠恒河为生
for over 40 years,but Sachin is no ordinary angler.
40多年来,Sachin都不是普通的钓鱼者.
He has a secret weapon.
他有一个秘密武器.
Otters.
水獭.
He's recruited some of nature's most talented fishermen
他招募了一些自然界最有才华的渔民
and trained them to herd fish into his nets.
并训练他们将鱼放到他的网中.
The fact that fish survive in this polluted river
鱼在这条被污染的河中生存的事实
is another indication
是另一个迹象
that Ganges water has unique properties.
恒河水具有独特的特性.
Today's catch is small,but profitable.
今天的渔获量很小,但有利可图.
Catfish can fetch over $30 each.
fish鱼每只可以卖到30美元以上.
This family of otters has been fishing with Sachin's family
这个水獭家族一直在和萨钦的家人一起钓鱼
for generations,but the men must still be careful.
世世代代,但男人们仍必须小心.
Even a friendly nip could take a man's finger clean off.
即使是友好的压区,也可能会使男人的手指脱掉.
Otters work hard and are well paid for their labor.
水獭辛勤工作,并且劳动报酬丰厚.
No matter how small the catch,they are first to be fed.
不管捕获的鱼有多小,它们都首先被喂食.
Back in their village,the otters get time time
回到他们的村庄,水獭会抽出时间
to take a dust bath with their pups.
和他们的幼崽去洗个澡.
This is their fourth litter,
这是他们的第四胎,
five healthy and boisterous males.
五位健康且精力旺盛的男性.
A second helping of fish keeps the family content.
鱼类的第二次帮助使家人满意.
The pups have a lot to learn yet about catching food.
幼犬有很多要学习的东西.
They're three months old and just about weaned.
他们三个月大,几乎断奶了.
Sachin's mother always lends a hand rearing the otters.
萨钦（Sachin）的母亲总是伸出一只手抚养水獭.
In a few weeks,
在几周之内,
these youngsters will begin their training
这些年轻人将开始他们的训练
and learn to fish with the humans.
并学习与人类一起钓鱼.
And when they're a year old,
当他们一岁的时候,
Sachin will sell them on.
萨钦将继续出售它们.
A good fishing otter can fetch over $200.
好的水獭可以卖到200美元以上.
Much of the fish Sachin catches is sold
萨钦捕捞的大部分鱼都被卖掉了
and transported downstream,
并运送到下游,
where it ends up in the markets
它最终在市场上的位置
of one of the largest urban agglomerations in the world.
世界上最大的城市群之一.
Kolkata is home to nearly 16 million people
加尔各答拥有近1600万人的住所
and sprawls along the Hooghly River,
沿着胡格利河（Hooghly River）蔓延,
the main branch of the Ganges that runs to the sea.
恒河的主要分支,通向大海.
Once capital of the British Raj,
曾经是英国王朝的首都,
Kolkata is now one of India's most diverse
加尔各答现在是印度最多元化的国家之一
and chaotic cities.
和混乱的城市.
Kolkata's lifeblood is its river,
加尔各答的命脉是河流,
which it depends on for trade,industry,
它取决于贸易,工业,
and hydroelectric power.
和水力发电.
The city is far removed from the wild Ganges
这座城市远离野性恒河
and it's a stark reminder of the huge demands put
这完全提醒人们提出了巨大的要求
on the river by man.
在河上的人.
But just 60 kilometers upstream,
但是上游只有60公里,
a recent discovery has provided a glimmer of hope
最近的发现给我们带来了一线希望
for the Ganges and its wildlife.
恒河及其野生动植物.
Gharials are making a comeback.
加里尔人正在卷土重来.
Thought to be extinct in this part of the river,
被认为在河的这部分已灭绝,
there have been no gharial sightings here for over 30 years,
30多年来,这里一直没有发现加里尔人的踪迹,
until now.
到现在.
Muted squeaks bring a female out of the water.
静音的吱吱声将一只雌性带出水面.
When they're ready to hatch,
当他们准备孵化时,
her young call out from inside their eggs.
她的年轻人从鸡蛋里面喊出来.
It's their mother's cue to give them a helping hand
母亲的帮忙是他们的帮忙
and dig them out.
挖出来
The little hatchlings pierce the leathery shell
小孵化器刺穿了皮革外壳
of their eggs with a tiny egg tooth
他们的蛋有一个小的蛋齿
that grows on the tip of their snouts.
在他们的鼻子上不断增长.
A female gharial cannot carry her young
雌性雀巢不能带她的年轻
to the water like other crocodilians.
像其他鳄鱼一样往水里去.
Her teeth are too shop.
她的牙齿太铺张.
The hatchlings need to make their own way to the river.
孵化场需要自己走到河边.
But one nest has been unearthed by the wrong reptile.
但是错误的爬行动物发现了一个巢穴.
A monitor lizard makes short work of a clutch of eggs.
监控蜥蜴会使鸡蛋紧紧地抓紧.
The mother moves quickly.
母亲动作很快.
But she's not quick enough.
但是她不够快.
This clutch has been unlucky,but others have survived.
这个离合器很不幸,但其他幸存者仍然幸存.
Less than 40 centimeters long when they hatch,
孵化时不到40厘米长,
newborn gharials are vulnerable to predators too,
新生儿的食性动物也容易受到食肉动物的攻击,
But their mother protects them for several weeks
但是他们的母亲保护了他们几个星期
while they learn to hunt.
他们学习狩猎时.
Juveniles feed on insects and small frogs.
幼虫以昆虫和小青蛙为食.
It will be a few years before
几年后
these miniature predators pose any threat to fish.
这些小型捕食者对鱼类构成任何威胁.
It's thought that there are now at least 100 gharials
认为现在至少有100个加里尔
living in this stretch of river.
住在这条河里.
If they're surviving here,so close to a big city,
如果他们还活着,离大城市这么近,
then there may yet be some hope for their future.
那么他们的未来可能还有一些希望.
The Ganges supplies trillions of gallons
恒河供应了数万亿加仑
of water for farming and industry,
用于农业和工业的水,
and flushes away the waste of millions of people.
并冲走了数百万人的浪费
Despite this,Hindus drink it every day
尽管如此,印度教徒每天都喝
and claim that far from making them ill,
并声称这并没有使他们生病,
it's good for physical and spiritual health.
对身体和精神健康都有好处.
Scientists have studied this paradox.
科学家已经研究了这种悖论.
The Ganges seems to contain a natural disinfectant,
恒河似乎含有天然消毒剂,
capable of killing pathogens that cause widespread disease.
能够杀死引起广泛疾病的病原体.
Research has identified the presence of bacteriophages,
研究发现存在噬菌体,
microscopic organisms that feed on bacteria.
以细菌为食的微观生物.
When they find food,
当他们找到食物时,
bacteriophages multiply incredibly quickly.
噬菌体迅速繁殖.
In less than half an hour,100 can become 100,000.
在不到半小时的时间内,100可以变成100,000.
The more people that enter the water,
越多的人进入水中,
the more food is available to the Ganges's bacteriophages
恒河的噬菌体可得到的食物越多
In an invisible feeding frenzy,
在看不见的喂食狂潮中,
they eliminate diseases before they spread.
它们在疾病传播之前就将其消除.
Tests also show
测试还显示
that the Ganges carries an unusually large amount
恒河携带大量异常
of dissolved oxygen.
溶解氧.
This helps break down the human and animal waste spewed
这有助于分解喷出的人畜废物
into the river.
进入河里.
The Ganges does this 25 times faster than any other river.
恒河做到这一点的速度比其他任何河流都要快25倍.
This could be the secret to the survival of animals here.
这可能是这里动物生存的秘密.
A high oxygen content sustains a healthy fish population,
高氧含量可以维持健康的鱼类种群,
which in turn supports the Ganges's aquatic animals,
反过来支持恒河的水生动物,
river dolphins,gharials,and otters.
河豚,鲸鱼和水獭.
And organic waste is broken down into nutrients
有机废物分解成养分
that are useful rather than harmful to the environment.
是有益的,而不是对环境有害.
On the border of India and Bangladesh,
在印度和孟加拉国的边界上,
the Ganges dissolves into the largest river delta on earth.
恒河溶入了地球上最大的河流三角洲.
Formed by the confluence of the Ganges,
由恒河汇合而成,
the Brahmaputra,and the Meghna rivers,
雅鲁藏布江和梅格纳河
this super delta is a labyrinth of channels and creeks.
这个超级三角洲是迷宫般的河道和小溪.
In it lies the largest tract
最大的区域在其中
of mangrove swamp and forest on earth.
红树林沼泽和地球上的森林.
The Sundarbans.
苏达班人.
Rivers wash mud and silt out into the Bay of Bengal,
河流冲刷泥浆并淤积到孟加拉湾,
ocean tides flood the forest with salt water every day.
海潮每天都使盐水淹没森林.
It's one of
这是其中之一
the world's most challenging natural environments.
世界上最具挑战性的自然环境.
The Sundarbans is a place where land meets sea
Sundarbans是陆地与海洋交汇的地方
and the line in between is blurred.
并且两者之间的线是模糊的.
Even the fish seem confused.
甚至鱼也似乎很困惑.
Mudskippers spend more time out of the water than in it.
挡泥板运动员在水中花费的时间多于在水中花费的时间.
Water stored in pouches stops their gills drying out
袋中储存的水可防止g干燥
and they can breathe through their skin
他们可以通过皮肤呼吸
as long as it's wet.
只要是湿的
Modified pectoral fins are strong enough
改良的胸鳍足够坚固
to pull them over the ground
把它们拉到地上
and they can skip a half a meter by flexing their tails.
他们可以弯曲尾巴跳过半米.
During the breeding season,
在繁殖季节
tensions run high and males defend their territories.
紧张局势加剧,男性捍卫自己的领土.
Blue markings become brighter.
蓝色标记变亮.
Dorsal fins wave like warning flags.
背鳍像警告标志一样挥舞.
If this fails to deter an intruder,
如果这不能阻止入侵者,
there's nothing left except mouth to mouth combat.
除了口口相传之外,别无其他.
Trees also have strange adaptations.
树木还具有奇特的适应性.
To escape the waterlogged soil,
为了逃脱积水的土壤,
their roots send up stalks,
他们的根发出茎,
which absorb oxygen from the atmosphere.
从大气中吸收氧气.
For a wild boar,
对于野猪,
the muddy Sundarbans's a paradise.
浑浊的桑达班人是天堂.
Chital deer look up rather than down for food
虎斑鹿仰视而不是仰望食物
and always keep an eye open for danger.
并时刻警惕危险.
With good reason.
有充分的理由.
In the Sundarbans,
在Sundarbans,
the tiger is still king of the jungle.
老虎仍然是丛林之王.
Stripes break up its outline
条纹打破了轮廓
and make it hard to spot through the trees.
并很难在树上发现.
Male tigers are the heaviest cats in the world.
雄虎是世界上最重的猫.
They can weigh over 200 kilos,
他们可能重达200公斤以上,
about three times more than the average human.
大约是普通人的三倍.
Paws the size of side plates spread their weight
爪子的大小可扩展侧板的重量
and help them move silently through the forest.
并帮助他们静静地穿过森林.
Tigers creep as close to prey as possible
老虎尽可能靠近猎物爬行
before launching an attack.
在发动攻击之前.
Thick mangroves provide plenty of cover.
茂密的红树林提供了足够的覆盖.
Chital deer are favorite targets.
鹿是最喜欢的目标.
Tiger's canines can grow to 10 centimeters,
老虎的犬齿可以长到10厘米,
the longest of any cat.
最长的猫.
They're so powerful they've been known
它们是如此强大,以至于广为人知
to bring down animals six times their own weight.
使动物体重减轻六倍.
The chital sense danger.
感觉上的危险.
Fleeing into water is usually a good tactic
逃入水中通常是个好策略
for escaping predators.
逃避掠食者.
But tigers don't mind getting wet.
但是老虎不介意弄湿.
Unlike most cats,they're excellent swimmers.
与大多数猫不同,它们是出色的游泳者.
With its catch back on dry land,
赶在干旱的土地上,
the big cat makes light work of its meal.
大猫在做饭.
A rough tongue scrapes meat clean off the bone
粗糙的舌头擦净了骨头上的肉
Today,the Sundarbans is home
今天,Sundarbans回来了
to the largest population of wild Bengal tigers in India.
印度最大的野生孟加拉虎种群.
Over 400.
超过400.
It's the only place on earth
这是地球上唯一的地方
where these big cats live in such an aquatic environment.
这些大猫生活在这样的水生环境中.
Tigers have embraced their watery world
老虎拥抱了他们的水世界
and will feed on fish and crabs,
会以鱼和螃蟹为食,
but there is something else on their menu.
但是他们的菜单上还有别的东西.
The Sundarbans tigers are notorious man eaters.
Sundarbans老虎是臭名昭著的食肉动物.
It's thought that as many as 250 people are killed
据认为有多达250人被杀
in tiger attacks here every year.
每年在这里遭受老虎袭击.
Foraging in the forest for honey or firewood can be fatal.
在森林里觅食蜂蜜或薪柴可能是致命的.
Some say a tiger can even pull a man from a boat.
有人说,老虎甚至可以从船上拉一个人.
Villagers have even been dragged from their beds.
村民们甚至被从床上拖了下来.
It's still not fully understood
仍然没有完全了解
why the tigers here are such a threat to man.
为什么这里的老虎对人类如此威胁.
People live close to tigers in other parts of India,
在印度其他地区,人们居住在靠近老虎的地方,
but nowhere else are fatalities so high.
但死亡人数如此之高.
One theory is they've developed a taste for human flesh
一种说法是他们已经对人肉产生了兴趣
after scavenging on the bodies of cyclone victims.
在清理旋风受害者的尸体后.
Devastating weather in the Bay of Bengal kills thousands
孟加拉湾的毁灭性天气造成数千人死亡
of people every year.
每年的人.
Or perhaps these tigers have never learned to fear man.
也许这些老虎从来没有学会惧怕人.
In the 20th century,
在20世纪,
big game hunting caused India's tiger population to crash
大型狩猎活动导致印度虎种群崩溃
from 40,000 to just 1800,
从40,000到1800
but impenetrable mangrove forest protected Sundarbans tigers
但坚不可摧的红树林保护着桑达班虎
from man and his guns.
从人和他的枪支.
Here,people are prey,
在这里,人们是猎物,
but each time a tiger takes a human life,
但是每一次老虎夺去人类的生命,
the precarious existence of its own kind is shaken.
自身不稳定的存在被动摇了.
Fear and reprisal leads to tigers being killed.
恐惧和报复导致老虎被杀死.
For a species on the brink of extinction,
对于濒临灭绝的物种,
every tiger death is a catastrophe.
每只老虎的死亡都是一场灾难.
A government conservation program works hard
政府的保护计划努力工作
to keep man and cat safe from each other.
保持人与猫之间的安全.
As home to one of the world's most endangered animals,
作为世界上最濒危的动物之一的家,
the Sundarbans will be protected
Sundarbans将受到保护
so people as well as tigers can benefit from it
因此人们和老虎都可以从中受益
for generations to come.
世世代代.
While the Sundarbans is one
而Sundarbans就是其中之一
of the world's great wildernesses,
世界上的大荒原,
a small island,just a few miles away,
几英里外的一个小岛,
hosts one of the planet's largest gatherings of people.
拥有地球上最大的人群聚会之一.
Sagar Island is the place
萨加尔岛（Sagar Island）是地方
where the Ganges finally reaches the sea
恒河最终到达大海的地方
and flows into the Bay of Bengal.
并流入孟加拉湾.
It's the middle of January
一月中旬
and this sleepy island is about
而这个昏昏欲睡的岛屿
to be transformed by an inundation.
被洪水淹没.
Not of water,but of people.
不是水,而是人.
This is a dramatic reminder of the pressure put
这极大地提醒了人们施加的压力
on the Ganges river and its wildlife by humans.
在恒河及其人类的野生动植物上.
Millions of Hindus arrive here
数以百万计的印度教徒到达这里
on the day of Makara Sankranti,the winter solstice.
冬至Makara Sankranti那天.
The Gangasagar Mela,as it is known,
众所周知,Gangasagar Mela,
is one of the largest religious gatherings on earth.
是地球上最大的宗教聚会之一.
Many travel for days to get here.
许多人要几天才能到达这里.
For some,it's the first time they've ever seen the sea.
对于某些人来说,这是他们第一次见过大海.
Tropical beaches are transformed
热带海滩变了
into the world's biggest campsite.
进入世界上最大的露营地.
Pilgrims throw coins as offerings for the goddess Ganga.
朝圣者投掷硬币作为女神恒河的祭品.
For enterprising children,
对于有进取心的孩子,
it's an opportunity worth braving the mud to exploit.
这是一个值得冒充开发的机会.
During the festival,they can make over 1000 rupees,
在节日期间,他们可以赚到超过1000卢比,
a healthy boost to often meager incomes,
经常收入微薄的健康增长,
Makara Sankranti is a harvest festival,
玛卡拉·桑克兰蒂（Makara Sankranti）是一个丰收节,
a time to give thanks to the Ganges
是时候感谢恒河了
for the crop she provides and livelihood she sustains.
她提供的农作物和维持的生计.
Sagar Island is regarded
萨加尔岛被认为
as one of the most auspicious places
作为最吉祥的地方之一
to bathe in Ganges water.
在恒河水中沐浴.
This is a grand farewell
这是一场盛大的告别
to a river that has played such a vital role
到扮演如此重要角色的河流
in the lives of India's people and wildlife.
在印度人民和野生动植物的生活中.
The Ganges is home to some of India's rarest creatures,
恒河是印度一些稀有生物的家园,
which fight for survival as man encroaches on wilderness.
当人类侵占荒野时,它们为生存而战.
Agriculture and industry have swallowed much
农业和工业吞没了很多
of the Ganges's fertile floodplain,once home to giants
恒河肥沃的洪泛区之一,曾经是巨人的家
like the Indian rhino.
像印度犀牛.
Millions of humans live and die on the riverbanks.
数以百万计的人在河岸上生活和死亡.
The Ganges is regarded not just as sacred,
恒河不仅被视为神圣,
but as a goddess in her own right.
但作为自己的女神
A dip in the holy river purifies the soul,
浸入圣河净化灵魂
but also pollutes the water,
而且会污染水,
but high levels of oxygen and disease-eating microorganisms
但是高水平的氧气和致病微生物
lend the scientific ring of truth to religious beliefs
将真理的科学环带给宗教信仰
in the cleansing powers of the Ganges.
在恒河的清洁力量中.
The river's unique properties nurture and sustain
这条河的独特属性孕育和维持着
a spectacular array of wildlife.
各种各样的野生动植物.
From death and decay come new beginnings on the Ganges.
从死亡和衰败开始,恒河就开始了新的起点.
India's great river of life.
印度的生命之河.